<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="ScienceSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<WebPage>
    <title>Space</title>
    <webDisc>Verge Science is here to bring you the most up-to-date space news and analysis, whether
        it’s about the latest findings from NASA or comprehensive coverage of the next SpaceX rocket
        launch to the International Space Station. We’ll take you inside the discoveries of new
        exoplanets, space weather, space policy, and the booming commercial space industry. </webDisc>

    <Intro>SPACE</Intro>
    <topArt>NASA collected a sample from an asteroid for the first time — here’s why it matters
        GEORGINA TORBET<time t="2 26 PM EDT">2:26 PM EDT</time>|5 <photo>OSIRIS-REx sample retrieval
            by NASA</photo></topArt>

    <article n="1">
        <icon>W</icon>
        <edtior name="WES DAVIS">WES DAVIS</edtior>
        <time t="12 24 PM EDT">12:24 PM EDT</time>

        <para>The OSIRIS-REx capsule is in the bag.NASA reports that the OSIRIS-REx capsule “has
            been bagged” and is flying suspended from a helicopter to the space agency’s clean lab
            to recover samples gathered from the Bennu asteroid in 2020. When it gets to NASA’s
            on-site clean room, scientists will remove the canister containing the sample to be
            opened at Johnson Space Center in Houston, Texas on Tuesday. Check out this gallery of
            screenshots from NASA’s live coverage. NASA had a photographer on site, so we’ll
            probably get some much nicer shots of the process soon.</para>



        <photoCount>1/5</photoCount>
    </article>

    <article n="2">
        <icon>W</icon>
        <editor name="WES DAVIS">WES DAVIS</editor>
        <time t="11 48 AM EDT">11:48 AM EDT</time>

        <pare>NASA is now recovering the capsule containing the Bennu asteroid sample.A team is
            preparing to take the OSIRIS-REx capsule back to NASA’s portable clean lab to collect
            the Bennu asteroid sample it gathered three years ago, according to NASA’s live
            coverage. Team members have also placed flags in the area to note potentially
            interesting environmental samples to collect in the area around the capsule for later
            examination.</pare>


        <disc>A group of four people stand near the OSIRIS-REx capsule.</disc>
        <credit>The NASA recovery team examines the OSIRIS-REx capsule prior to beginning official
            recovery operations. Screenshot: Wes Davis / The Verge</credit>
    </article>

    <article n="3">
        <icon>W</icon>
        <editor name="WES DAVIS">WES DAVIS</editor>
        <time t="11 28 AM EDT">11:28 AM EDT</time>

        <para>OSIRIS-REx is safe for approach.Lockheed Martin crew checked it for dangerous heat,
            off-gassing, and unexploded ordinance at the site of the capsule to make sure it poses
            no danger to the team recovering the OSIRIS-REx samples. They’ve now declared it safe to
            approach, so NASA will now prepare to pick it up.</para>


        <disc>Two people standing near the capsule, examining it for any danger.</disc>
        <credit>Lockheed Martin safety team members check the capsule to ensure it’s safe to
            approach. Screenshot: Wes Davis / The Verge</credit>
    </article>

    <article n="4">
        <icon>W</icon>
        <editor name="WES DAVIS">WES DAVIS</editor>
        <time t="11 16 AM EDT">11:16 AM EDT</time>

        <para>The OSIRIS-REx capsule has been located.The OSIRIS-REx helicopter team has confirmed
            the location of the capsule containing the Bennu asteroid sample. The capsule touched
            down at about <time t="10 52AM ET">10:52AM ET</time>. The first helicopter has landed
            and the team is beginning recovery of the capsule as soon as they can verify there is no
            danger of injury from unexploded ordinance.</para>


        <disc>A picture of the OSIRIS-REx capsule at its landing site.</disc>
        <credit>The OSIRIS-REx capsule sitting in the Utah desert. Screenshot: Wes Davis / The
            Verge</credit>
    </article>

    <article n="5">
        <icon>W</icon>
        <icon>1</icon>
        <editor name="WES DAVIS">WES DAVIS</editor>
        <time t="10 57 AM EDT">10:57 AM EDT </time>
        <para>The OSIRIS-REx capsule has touched down.The “time capsule to our ancient solar system”
            from the OSIRIS-REx mission has officially touched down in the Utah desert. NASA’s live
            coverage notes it landed about three minutes sooner than expected. The team is now
            heading to it with helicopters to begin the process of gathering the samples.</para>
    </article>
</WebPage>
