<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="LeavesSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<poem>
    <title>Leaves</title>
    <intro>Add this poem to an anthology Lloyd Schwartz 1941 – </intro>
    <!-- a published collection of poems or other pieces of writing. -->

    <Ind>1</Ind>
    <Stanza s="1">Every <Cont Info="Setting">October</Cont> it becomes important, no, necessary to
        see the leaves turning, to be surrounded by leaves turning; it's not just the symbolism, to
        confront in the death of the year your death, one blazing farewell appearance, though the
        irony isn't lost on you that nature is most seductive when it's about to die, flaunting the
        dazzle of its incipient exit, an ending that at least so far the effects of human progress
            <LoI>(pollution, acid rain)</LoI> have not yet frightened you enough to make you believe
        is real; that is, you know this ending is a deception because of course nature is always
        renewing itself— the trees don't die, they just pretend, go out in style, and return in
        style: a new style.<!-- I came back to mark these words because it was interesting how the author uses man made things like pollution or acid rain in the first stanza yet in the last one it brings up fire a more natural  --> </Stanza>
    

    <Ind>2</Ind>
    <Stanza s="2">Is it deliberate how far they make you go especially if you live in the city to
        get far enough away from home to see not just trees but only trees? <Cont Info="Setting">The
            boring highways, roadsigns</Cont>, high speeds, 10-axle trucks passing you as if they
        were in an even greater hurry than you to look at leaves: so you drive in terror for literal
        hours and it looks like rain, or snow, but it's probably just clouds (too cloudy to see any
        color?) and you wonder, <LoI>given the poverty of your memory</LoI>, which road had the most
        color last year, but it doesn't matter since you're probably too late anyway, or too early—
        whichever road you take will be the wrong one and you've probably come all this way for
        nothing. <!-- "Poverty of your memory" is a great way of describe someone lack of memories--></Stanza>
    

    <Ind>3</Ind>
    <Stanza s="3">You'll be driving along depressed when suddenly a cloud will move and <Cont
            Info="Setting">the sun will muscle through and ignite the hills.</Cont> It may not last.
        Probably won't last. But for a moment the whole world comes to. Wakes up. Proves it lives.
        It lives— red, yellow, orange, brown, russet, ocher, vermilion, gold. Flame and rust. Flame
        and rust, <LoI>the permutations of burning. You're on fire. Your eyes are on fire.</LoI> It
        won't last, you don't want it to last. You can't stand any more. But you don't want it to
        stop. It's what you've come for. It's what you'll come back for. It won't stay with you, but
        you'll remember that it felt like nothing else you've felt or something you've felt that
        also didn't last.<!-- I love how the mundane drive turns into an overwhelming flame of color thats so different from what this person is used to seeing it looking at it hurts in a way --></Stanza>
    
    <copyright>Copyright © 1992 by Lloyd Schwartz. From Goodnight, Gracie (The University of Chicago
        Press, 1992). Appears courtesy of the author.</copyright>
</poem>
